



**SONAL THAKKAR** (650 469 2267):

SONALTHAKKAR@GMAIL.COM HTTPS://www.linkedin.com/in/sonalthakkar

Pursuing master's degree in Data Science at UC Berkeley. An Oracle Certified Professional (OCP) -Techno-Functional Lead with over 12 years of experience designing, developing and testing multi-tiered ERP systems with a focus on data analytics. Experience working on Oracle Applications Implementations and Upgrades. Python developer for complex ETL processes.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Solar Mosaic Inc., Oakland, CA

Oracle Technical Lead

Mar 2017 - to date

- Built a Matillion ETL project GL Journal Entries pulling data from both legacy systems Northridge System (NLS) and Platform (built using in-house Scala). This data then feeds into Redshift database and then into Oracle GL.
- Created an end-to-end data pipeline with data mangling and transformations on Airflow-Python-Spark for automated journal entries into Oracle ERP using Hadoop to MapReduce the large data extracts.
- Created AP Payment template for Wells Fargo check payment coming into Oracle (fusion) AP module.
- Created new and maintained existing Periscope reports and dashboards.

Sunrun, San Francisco, CA

Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2015 – Feb 2017

- Designed and built Kyriba integration projects to create custom interfaces into 3<sup>rd</sup> party tool Kyriba for AP, AR and GL and interfaces from 3<sup>rd</sup> party into Oracle for GL journals and AP check reconciliation.
- Set up communication tunnel between Oracle SF, Oracle SLO and Kyriba for data transmission.
- Created customizations for R12.1.1 Financials and OLFM modules, including interfaces, reports and OA page personalization.

Google through eTouch

Senior Consultant

Dec 2013 - July 2015

- Collaborated with the BI Group on Big Data Query and Big Tables. Creating Big Query table structures for a project to track logistics and implementing the same on BO. Charted out the facts and dimensions and ensuring design integrity through entity-relationship diagrams following the snowflake or star schema.
- Designed and developed end-to-end solutions for reporting needs for inventory management for Google Glass. This included coding on custom tools and generating data from Oracle EBS and custom data sources into custom reporting platforms. Created complex techno-functional documentation spanning platforms to ensure a single view of business requirement and the technical details of the object created.
- Partnered with the data mining team to cater to reporting needs across Google products. This included Java code and Oracle PL/SQL.

Deloitte Consulting., Bangalore, India

Consultant

Jan 2011 – Oct 2013

Designed and developed end to end complex custom solutions along with preparing technical and installation documents (AIM-MD70, MD120, T20). Creating shell scripts for migration of code across instances.

Project: Weight Watchers/Oracle Apps 11.5.10.2

- Offshore project manager and technical lead for a team of 5 resources.
- Developed and delivered complex customer and AR invoice interface, reports and extensions.
- As a team successfully delivered 12+ financial and SCM objects which include OAF objects including: rdf and xml reports, customized AP Invoice approval workflow, interfaces ahead of time.

# Sonal Thakkar

Oracle India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India

Senior Software Engineer

Sept 2008 – Jan 2011

- Supported global customers in the E-Business Suite Application.
- Demonstrated ability to set up procure to pay cycle, which included setting up financial and payables options, entering payables invoices, matching with associated PO/receipt, define various payment methods (EFT, wire, check) and posting to GL.
- Received Level 2 Award for FY11 Q2 for providing training on R12 concepts.

The Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, WI Oracle ERP Programmer/Analyst

May 2007 – Aug 2008

- Developed custom XML Publisher reports for Faculty Affairs project
- Determined requirements, estimate, design and document requirements in MD050, MD070s, MD120 and BR100 implementation documents as a part of AIM methodology. Set-up Value-sets and Concurrent requests, develop and test Oracle functions, procedures and reports.

Johns Hopkins Alumni and Development Services, Baltimore, MD

May 2006 – May 2007

 Designed, developed, tested and documented custom reports and forms, including mail-merge reports for ALADIN using Oracle Reports Builder, to be integrated with Oracle Forms 10g front-end.

Danish Road Directorate, CIBERsites Inc., Oklahoma City, OK

Feb 2006 - Apr 2006

• Designed, developed and tested reports using Oracle Reports 10g, to be integrated on Java-J2EE front-end.

Worked in India between May 2001 and August 2003 as a permanent employee in IT companies in Kolkata as a Visual Basic, SQL Server, and Crystal Reports 7.0 Developer.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of California, Berkeley Master of Information and Data Science (MIDS): 2018-2020, GPA - 4.0

Master of Business Management (MBM), Calcutta University, India: Specialization in Operations Research and Systems Analysis

Bachelor of Science, St. Xavier's College, Calcutta University, India: Economics, Mathematics, Statistics

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

**ERP:** Oracle Apps 11i, 12i, Fusion

**Programming Languages:** Python, PL/SQL

Database Platform: Oracle, Redshift/PostgresSQL, Hive, MySQL

Reporting/ETL Tools: XML Publisher, Oracle Reports 6i/10g, Matillion, Airflow, Spark, Hadoop

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Oracle Certified Professional (OCP) - Application Developer - SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle Forms 6i, Oracle Reports 6i

**Sun Java Certification** – Sun Certified Java Programmer for the java 2 platform 1.4

Sun Java Certification – Sun Certified Java Web Component Developer for the java 2 platform 1.4

**Brainbench Certification** – Java 2 Fundamentals